Richard McConnell

🗣 Franklin, Tennessee, United States 🗷 mr.mcconnellr@gmail.com 🚨 (330)-432-5235 🛅 https://www.linkedin.com/in/richard-mcconnell/

https://github.com/richardmcconnell12

SUMMARY

My journey toward software development has been a wondrous adventure that has opened my eyes to a level of opportunity that I did not believe was out there. While I have always been interested in computers and technology most of my life, I had no previous knowledge of web development. I studied Computer Assisted Drafting, and that is where I began to wonder how the programs I used were made. I was fascinated with the functionality and algorithms used to solve a given problem.

When I was introduced to programming, I had a feeling that this would be a field that would interest me. I was ecstatic to explore a path that I could continuously challenge myself as well as, exercise logical skills to solve problems that would impact and help others.

EXPERIENCE

Junior React Developer

Auction Edge Inc.

Oct. 2019 - Nov. 2019, Franklin, TN

- · Authored new features and version control with Git, and source code management through BitBucket.
- Effectively developed reusable components based on specific design specifications using ReactJS and Typescript for future use.
- · Queried API database through the use of GraphQL.

Full-Stack Software Developer

Nashville Softare School

November 2018 - September 2019, Nashville, TN

- $\cdot \text{Implemented object-oriented programming through daily coding exercises and extended projects simulating real world business challenges and problems.}$
- · HTML, CSS, JavaScript and React Implemented full CRUD, browser-based, single-paged applications by dictating the content, style, and functionality. Utilized JavaScript fundamentals by leveraging modular, readable code and reusable components.
- $\cdot \text{API-Utilized JSON server in several projects to interact with local and third-party API's, and developed RESTful API's using C\#/.NET, SQL, and LINQ. \\$
- · Monitored workflow and automation through the terminal using Grunt, Linting with ESLint, module bundling with Browserfy.
- · Authored source code and version-control of projects through Git/GitHub
- · Developed and performed quality assurance activities utilizing TDD methodologies
- \cdot NPM Managed Tool Packages in various applications and projects
- · Soft Skills Facilitated in planning application architecture using white -boarding, AGILE and SCRUM methodologies, and promoting a positive work culture with a growth mindset and collaboration.

Customer Service Specialist

Target

July 2017 - October 2018, Massillon, OH

- · Carried out logistic orders using effective inventory controll processes, and product quality assurance.
- · Optimized service delivery by prioritization of tasks at hand, by impact and urgency.
- $\cdot \text{Contributed to the success of new employees through training in daily routines, logistics, and effective communication with both guests and employees.}\\$

Server and Bartender

Sammy Sues Barbeque

June 2014 - July 2017, Dover, OH

- $\cdot \text{Trained new employees on working within the team and communicate effectively, along with tending to guest, and providing a clear understanding of daily practices and routines.}$
- · Completed minimum prep require prior to each shift to reduce inefficiencies.
- Frequently assisted colleagues during rush periods to promote teamwork while providing exceptional service and gues dining experience.

SKILLS

Front End: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, ReactJS, Redux, AngularJS, NextJS, Material UI, MaterializeCSS, Bootstrap 4, Firebase Back End: C#, .NET Core, ASP.NET, ADO.NET, LINQ, Microsoft SQL Server, MVC, Entity Framework.

Tools: Git/GitHub, BitBucket, JSON-Server, Browserfy, Grunt, Visual Studio, Visual Studio Code, NPM, Postman, Azure Data Studio.

EDUCATION

Full-Stack Software Development Certification Nashville Software School · Nashville, TN · 2019

CAD Engineering Certification

PROJECTS

Furever Friends - github.com/richardmcconnell12/REACT-FureverFriends

A pet adoption application that bridges the gap between user's and adoptable pets located in the Greater Nashville area. As an advocate in the "adopt, don't shop" philosophy, this application allows to find a home for their perfect pet. A personalized interest list along with the ability to take notes on their chosen animals allow for a simple and immersive experience to find a pet that is right for them.

- Used React. js and React-Router to create a full CRUD application with simple authenication.
- · Utilized Material-UI and vanilla CSS to organize a single page layout with dynamic widgets and modals.
- Implemented JSON-Server to create a flat data structure along side a third-party API.

The Perfect Batch - github.com/richardmcconnell12/The-Perfect-Batch

The perfect recipe tracker targeted toward users that often go off the cuff when it making a recipe. Answering common questions of "how did you make this?" or "What should I make?" Users can authorize an account, and input their recipes to track how they made the perfect batch. User are also granted access to other created recipes.

- Generated full CRUD capability with C# and .NET Core frameworks.
- Implemented Microsoft SQL Server to create a flat data structure with .NET's ORM.
- Generated Razor Pages and JavaScript for HTML templating.
- · Used BootStrap 4 for styling a simple, elegant user experience.